<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tab id="t.0" title="Overview" index="0">
  <body>
    <sectionbreak sectionType="CONTINUOUS" contentDirection="LEFT_TO_RIGHT" columnSeparatorStyle="NONE" />
    <title>ExtraSuite Docs</title>
    <subtitle>The AI-native workflow for Google Workspace</subtitle>
    <p></p>
    <h1>What is ExtraSuite?</h1>
    <p><b>ExtraSuite</b> is an open-source CLI tool built for AI agents. It provides a secure, token-efficient, and auditable way to read and write Google Workspace files — Docs, Sheets, Slides, and Forms — using a simple <b>pull / edit / push</b> workflow.</p>
    <p>Instead of navigating the complex Google APIs directly, agents work with plain files on disk. ExtraSuite handles the translation between those files and the live Google document.</p>
    <p></p>
    <h1>How It Works</h1>
    <p>The core workflow has four steps:</p>
    <li type="decimal" level="0"><b>Pull</b> — Download the Google file and convert it into a local folder of readable files.</li>
    <li type="decimal" level="0"><b>Edit</b> — Modify the local files directly. No API knowledge required.</li>
    <li type="decimal" level="0"><b>Diff</b> — Preview what changes will be sent to Google. No network calls.</li>
    <li type="decimal" level="0"><b>Push</b> — Apply the changes to the live Google document via the API.</li>
    <p></p>
    <h1>Key Innovations</h1>
    <p></p>
    <h2>Git-like Workflow</h2>
    <p>ExtraSuite brings a <b>git-inspired pull/diff/push</b> model to all Google Drive file types. Every pull captures a pristine snapshot so the diff engine knows exactly what changed.</p>
    <h2>Unique Agent Identity</h2>
    <p>Each employee's agent gets a <b>dedicated 1:1 service account</b>. The agent only has access to files explicitly shared with it. All changes appear in Google Drive's version history under that identity.</p>
    <h2>Secure Token Handling</h2>
    <p>Agents <i>never</i> see raw tokens. The ExtraSuite server issues short-lived credentials using OIDC and domain-wide delegation. Tokens are cached locally and refreshed automatically.</p>
    <h2>Token Efficient</h2>
    <p>Files are serialized into compact, <b>LLM-readable formats</b> — XML for Docs, TSV for Sheets, SML for Slides — so agents consume fewer tokens than working with raw API JSON.</p>
    <p></p>
    <h1>Supported Modules</h1>
    <li type="bullet" level="0"><b>extradoc</b> — Google Docs with full paragraph, table, and list support</li>
    <li type="bullet" level="0"><b>extrasheet</b> — Google Sheets with formula and formatting support</li>
    <li type="bullet" level="0"><b>extraslide</b> — Google Slides with shape and layout support</li>
    <li type="bullet" level="0"><b>extraform</b> — Google Forms for reading and editing form questions</li>
    <li type="bullet" level="0"><b>Gmail</b> — Draft creation via delegated OAuth</li>
    <li type="bullet" level="0"><b>Calendar</b> — Event management via delegated OAuth</li>
    <p></p>
  </body>
</tab>
