<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tab id="t.0" title="Version 1" index="0">
  <body>
    <sectionbreak sectionType="CONTINUOUS" contentDirection="LEFT_TO_RIGHT" columnSeparatorStyle="NONE" />
    <p>
      <t>This Markdown format organizes the 23 project ideas into detailed "Project Specification Cards." This structure is ideal for a bootcamp handbook or a GitHub repository readme, providing clear boundaries for each project while maintaining the "information-dense" requirements needed to challenge AI-assisted interns.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h1 headingId="h.vo28elc9ysws">
      <t>Backend Internship Bootcamp: Project Specifications</t>
    </h1>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Tech Stack:</b>
      </t>
      <t> FastAPI, SQLAlchemy, Google Cloud, Docker, Temporal, Cloud Storage.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <table>
      <col />
      <col />
      <col />
      <tr class="tr1">
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Original Title</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>New Specialized Title</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>What Does It Do?</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>E-Commerce Catalog</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>B2B FMCG Hyperlocal Distributor Engine</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A B2B engine for urban FMCG distributors serving 10k+ Kirana stores with dynamic pricing and credit logic.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Task Management</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Solar Farm EPC &amp; O&amp;M Field Ops Suite</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>An industrial task orchestrator for engineering firms managing distributed solar assets across rural India.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Healthcare Booking</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Geriatric Home-Care Managed Network</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A high-touch platform coordinating home-based palliative care involving doctors, nurses, and therapists.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Online Learning</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Vernacular Vocational Upskilling Portal</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A multi-lingual skilling platform for India's blue-collar workforce, focusing on certification and placement.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Restaurant Management</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Multi-brand Cloud Kitchen Orchestrator</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A backend for managing multi-brand kitchens with unified inventory and 3rd-party aggregator sync.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Social Media Feed</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Agri-Advisory Community &amp; Pest-Alerts</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A localized social network for Indian farmers with expert-verified advisory and geo-targeted alerts.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Expense Tracker</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>GST-Compliant Construction Petty Cash</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A specialized expense system for site supervisors to track cash-burn and vendor payouts in infra projects.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Real Estate Listing</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Fractional Commercial Real Estate (CRE)</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A platform for retail investors to buy 'slices' of high-yield commercial properties with monthly dividends.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Event Management</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Boutique Wedding Vendor &amp; Milestone Hub</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A high-end platform for managing large-scale Indian weddings, vendor contracts, and milestone payments.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Recruitment Mgmt</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>High-Volume Gig-Worker Onboarding</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A recruitment backend for onboarding 1,000+ delivery partners daily, including BGV and training.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Inventory Mgmt</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Cold-Chain Pharma Distribution Ledger</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A specialized inventory system for temperature-sensitive drugs with batch-level IoT traceability.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Fitness Tracking</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Insurance-Linked Corporate Wellness</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A backend aggregating wearable data to calculate Health Scores that influence insurance premiums.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Customer Support</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Fintech Transaction Dispute Manager</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A mission-critical support system for a Neobank handling UPI failures and NPCI-linked timelines.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Library Management</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>IP-Focused Legal Research &amp; Archive</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A digital repository for top-tier law firms handling litigation archives, case laws, and internal IP.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Hotel Booking</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Corporate Managed-Stay Orchestrator</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A B2B booking engine for IT firms to manage employee travel across partner hotels and guest houses.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Blog &amp; CMS</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Pharma Regulatory Compliance SOPs</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A specialized CMS for pharma plants to manage Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) and FDA logs.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Vehicle Fleet Mgmt</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>EV Fleet Battery-Swapping Hub</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A real-time telematics system for electric 3-wheelers, optimizing for battery life and charging cycles.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Survey &amp; Feedback</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Automotive Post-Purchase 'VoC'</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A feedback system for automobile dealerships to track CSAT across Sales and Service milestones.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Subscription Mgmt</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Gated Community Utility &amp; Maintenance</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A SaaS platform for RWAs to manage monthly maintenance, water-meter billing, and facility subs.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Food Delivery</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Hospital Diet-Kitchen Automation</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A food ordering system for hospitals, mapping meals to patient medical records and dietetics.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Notification Service</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Fintech 'Circuit-Breaker' Alerting</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A high-throughput notification engine for stock trading, handling volatility alerts and trade confirms.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Document Mgmt</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Real Estate Title-Deed &amp; Lien Registry</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A digital locker for developers and banks to manage project titles, encumbrances, and liens.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>Marketplace API</t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>
              <b>Industrial B2B Scrap Auction House</b>
            </t>
          </p>
        </td>
        <td>
          <p>
            <t>A marketplace for manufacturing plants to auction industrial waste to certified PCB-verified recyclers.</t>
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </table>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h2 headingId="h.8ttx1pu3llwn">
      <t>Detailed Project Requirements</t>
    </h2>
    <h3 headingId="h.ki0saqn5iebs">
      <t>1. B2B FMCG Hyperlocal Distributor Engine</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A B2B catalog and ordering system for an FMCG distributor serving Kirana stores with tiered pricing and basic credit management.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Build a product catalog with multiple SKUs, each mapped to a fixed GST rate (5%, 12%, or 18%). Implement three store pricing tiers (Regular, Silver, Gold) with percentage discounts off the base price. Order creation must enforce credit limits — block new orders from stores whose outstanding balance exceeds their assigned limit. Deduct inventory on order confirmation and allow a supervisor to manually adjust stock levels.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Handle partial deliveries where only some SKUs are fulfilled; regenerate the invoice for delivered items only. Prevent ordering out-of-stock products. Provide an order history view and an outstanding dues report per store.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.8qggkchu7oan">
      <t>2. Solar Farm EPC &amp; O&amp;M Field Operations Suite</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A task management system for engineering firms managing solar installation projects with phase-based tracking and SLA monitoring.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Build a project management system with a three-level hierarchy: Project &gt; Phase &gt; Task. Tasks support predecessor dependencies — Task B cannot start until Task A is marked complete. Implement SLA tracking for maintenance tickets: Critical tickets must be acknowledged within 4 hours and resolved within 48 hours, with email alerts when deadlines approach.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Handle Material Shortage holds that pause a task with a mandatory reason. Implement multi-role access for Client, Contractor, and Sub-contractor. Support milestone-based invoicing where a contractor can raise an invoice only after the client marks a phase milestone as complete.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.mw071eq5fh7m">
      <t>3. Geriatric Home-Care Managed Network</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A healthcare scheduling platform for home-based care plans with recurring practitioner assignments and basic schedule management.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Patients subscribe to recurring care plans (e.g., daily nurse visits for 30 days). Each appointment is assigned a primary practitioner and a backup. Implement simple schedule conflict detection to prevent double-booking a practitioner. Support a refund policy: full refund if cancelled more than 24 hours in advance, 50% refund if cancelled within 6 hours.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Send a Missed Check-in alert if a nurse has not marked a visit as started 30 minutes after the scheduled time. Implement basic qualification filtering so only nurses with the required certifications can be assigned to specialized patients. Store patient PII (history, prescriptions) in Cloud Storage with role-based access control.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.7gnr7q9f91jm">
      <t>4. Vernacular Vocational Upskilling Portal</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> An online learning platform with multi-language course support, module prerequisites, and automated certificate generation.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Courses are organized into modules with prerequisites. Support multi-language content — display titles and descriptions in the learner's preferred language. Learners must complete modules in order; the next module unlocks only after the current one is marked complete. Generate a PDF certificate upon course completion, stored in Cloud Storage for download.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Implement resume-from-last-position so learners can continue on any device. Support employer-sponsored enrollment where a company admin can bulk-create and assign learner accounts. Validate that a learner has met all prerequisite modules before allowing enrollment in an advanced course.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.d2pngpgq3r38">
      <t>5. Multi-brand Cloud Kitchen Orchestration Engine</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> An order management backend for a cloud kitchen running 2-3 brands from a single kitchen with shared ingredient inventory.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Track a shared ingredient inventory across all brands. When an ingredient drops below a minimum threshold, auto-mark all affected menu items across all brands as Out of Stock. Implement an order state machine: Placed &gt; Confirmed &gt; Preparing &gt; Ready &gt; Delivered or Cancelled. Support time-based menu availability where certain items are only offered during specific hours.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Implement Void Order functionality with mandatory reason codes and supervisor confirmation. Log ingredient consumption per order to enable basic COGS reporting. Notify a manager when any order has been in Preparing state for more than 30 minutes.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.7dkgrlnweq56">
      <t>6. Agri-Advisory Community &amp; Pests-Alert Network</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A social feed for farmers with geo-tagged posts, expert verification badges, and moderator-broadcast district-level alerts.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Farmers tag posts by crop type and district. The feed shows posts filtered to the farmer's registered crop and location, ordered by recency. Implement an Expert Verification badge that a moderator can apply to a post, marking it as Verified Advisory. Support image uploads for crop or pest photos stored in Cloud Storage.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Apply post rate-limiting to prevent spam (max 5 posts per user per day). Allow moderators to broadcast a geo-targeted alert to all farmers in a selected district. Validate posts against a keyword blocklist for basic community guideline enforcement.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.u8vlm3cfkgpk">
      <t>7. GST-Compliant Construction Petty Cash Manager</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> An expense tracking system for construction site supervisors with budget head constraints and a two-level approval workflow.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Supervisors submit expenses tagged to a budget head (e.g., Cement, Labour). Each expense requires a receipt photo uploaded to Cloud Storage. Implement a two-level approval workflow: Site Manager then Project Manager. Budget heads have monthly limits; submitting an expense when the limit is exhausted is blocked until a Change Order is approved.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Track Advance to Vendor payments as open items until a matching final invoice is submitted. Validate that expenses are submitted within 7 days of the purchase date. Provide a basic CSV export of all expenses per project per month for accounting purposes.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.8pvz3qrlkyvx">
      <t>8. Fractional Commercial Real Estate (CRE) Investment Platform</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A platform for retail investors to purchase fractional units in commercial properties and receive monthly dividend distributions.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A property is divided into a fixed number of investable units with a minimum purchase of 1 unit. Implement a simple investor registration flow with manual KYC document upload reviewed by an admin. Calculate and record monthly dividend distributions per investor based on unit holdings and the rental income entered by the admin. Store property title deeds and related documents in Cloud Storage with investor-only access.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>If a property does not reach 100% subscription within 60 days, flag all invested funds for refund processing. Implement a basic Resale Listing feature where investors can list units for other registered investors to purchase directly. Maintain an immutable audit log of all investment and payout transactions.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.47esgiqmy2uz">
      <t>9. Boutique Wedding Vendor &amp; Milestone Orchestrator</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A vendor and budget management tool for wedding planners with milestone-based payment tracking and a basic guest list.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Vendors are added with a total contract value broken into payment milestones (e.g., 20% advance, 40% mid-event, 40% post-event). Track milestone payment status and send reminders for upcoming due dates. Implement a guest list with dietary preferences (Veg, Non-Veg, Jain, Vegan). Show a real-time budget variance report: total committed spend vs. the overall budget cap.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Warn when a vendor is already booked on the same event date across any managed event. Validate that total vendor commitments do not exceed the budget cap before finalizing a new contract. Store uploaded vendor contract PDFs in Cloud Storage linked to the vendor record.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.rz6t5t29eslh">
      <t>10. High-Volume Gig-Worker Onboarding &amp; BGV Engine</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A multi-stage onboarding workflow for delivery partners with document upload, automated reminders, and admin review at each stage.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Implement a four-stage onboarding funnel: Registration &gt; Document Upload &gt; Training &gt; Active. Track required document uploads (ID proof, vehicle license, photo). Send automated email or SMS reminders if a candidate has not progressed from their current stage within 48 hours. An admin must review and approve or reject each candidate to advance them to the next stage.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Prevent duplicate registrations using the same phone number or ID document number. Support Re-activation of previously inactive workers without requiring full re-onboarding. Store all uploaded documents in Cloud Storage with time-bound access links that expire after 30 days.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.fwoo9s2rq0hq">
      <t>11. Cold-Chain Pharmaceutical Distribution Ledger</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A batch-level inventory system for temperature-sensitive pharmaceuticals with FEFO dispatch logic and expiry tracking.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Implement FEFO (First-Expiry-First-Out) dispatch logic when fulfilling orders. Track inventory at the batch level: each batch records manufacturing date, expiry date, and allowed storage temperature range. Flag batches with fewer than 30 days to expiry with a Near-Expiry alert. Allow daily manual temperature log entries per batch location; flag any entry outside the allowed range.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Given a batch ID, the system must list every outbound order that included units from that batch (Product Recall traceability). Implement basic inter-warehouse transfer requests when one location has excess stock. Store Certificate of Analysis (CoA) documents per batch in Cloud Storage, accessible to pharmacies.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.rki5i7ihcc2l">
      <t>12. Insurance-Linked Corporate Wellness Platform</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> An employee wellness platform with manual activity logging, a monthly challenge leaderboard, and anonymized departmental health reports for HR.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Employees manually log daily activities (steps, exercise duration, type). Assign wellness points based on activity logs measured against monthly goals. Run monthly company-wide challenges with a leaderboard ranked by points. Allow HR to view aggregated, anonymized health scores per department without seeing individual employee data.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Implement Medical Exemption: an employee can upload a doctor's note (stored in Cloud Storage) to pause challenge participation without losing their streak. Flag any single-day log where reported steps exceed 30,000 for admin review. Validate that total incentive payouts for the quarter do not exceed the pre-set reward pool budget.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.xr7twy76dmr3">
      <t>13. Fintech Transaction Dispute &amp; Chargeback Manager</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A customer support ticket system for transaction disputes with SLA-driven escalation and auto-refund for known technical failures.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Each support ticket is linked to a transaction ID and categorized (Failed Payment, Refund Delay, Unauthorized Charge). Implement two-tier SLA escalation: unresolved tickets auto-escalate to a senior agent after 48 hours, then to a manager after 72 hours. Support auto-refund for a pre-configured list of Technical Decline error codes without manual intervention. Apply basic PII masking in ticket logs, showing only the last 4 digits of an account or card number.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>When more than 20 tickets share the same error code within one hour, group them automatically into a single Incident record for bulk response. Generate a resolution summary report for each closed ticket for audit purposes. Route tickets categorized as Suspected Fraud to a dedicated Risk Team queue.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.gbhimilb60i3">
      <t>14. IP-Focused Digital Legal Research &amp; Archive</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A document management system for a law firm with matter-level access control, metadata search, billable time tracking, and retention policies.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Documents are organized by Matter (case). A lawyer assigned to Matter A cannot view documents from Matter B. Implement metadata search across documents (title, tags, upload date, matter name). Track time logged per matter per lawyer for billing purposes. Documents are stored in Cloud Storage and can be previewed in-browser.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Flag documents older than 7 years for retention review and archival. Implement Read Confirmation: certain documents require a Reviewed acknowledgment from the assigned lawyer before a task can be closed. Prevent document deletion without an explicit approval from a senior partner, and log all deletion requests.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.24c0nf29hcd7">
      <t>15. Corporate Managed-Stay &amp; Guesthouse Orchestrator</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A hotel booking system for corporate employees with grade-based rate caps, project cost center tagging, and an out-of-policy approval workflow.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Enforce booking policies based on employee grade — lower grades have lower nightly rate caps. Every booking must be tagged to a project cost center. If a booking exceeds the grade's allowed rate, trigger an approval request to the employee's manager that expires in 24 hours. Generate a basic GST invoice for each stay.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Apply a discounted rate from day 8 onwards for stays exceeding 7 consecutive nights. Allow certain rooms to be marked permanently reserved for on-call engineers. Store employee trip documents in Cloud Storage with automatic deletion 30 days after the trip end date.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.pay09xjof478">
      <t>16. Pharma Regulatory Compliance Knowledge Base</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A version-controlled SOP management system for pharma plants with read-receipt compliance and periodic review reminders.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Once an SOP is marked Approved, it is locked from editing; any change creates a new version with a full change history log. Factory workers must digitally acknowledge they have read a new SOP version before it is marked Active. QA leads receive email reminders 30 days before an SOP's scheduled periodic review date. Implement basic cross-linking between related SOPs.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Support an Emergency Override where a manager can mark an SOP as Under Review during a critical incident, notifying all relevant staff. All SOPs must be exportable as PDF with the viewer's name and access timestamp as a watermark. Prevent deletion of any approved SOP version; only archival is permitted.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.e74yp3bzba6h">
      <t>17. EV Fleet Battery-Swapping &amp; Telematics Hub</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A fleet management system where drivers log shift data, battery health is tracked manually, and payouts are calculated based on kilometers driven.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Drivers log vehicle data at the start and end of each shift: odometer reading, battery charge level, and route taken. Calculate driver payouts based on kilometers driven per shift. Flag a battery for service when its manually reported health metric drops below 70%. Implement mileage-based maintenance scheduling: flag a vehicle for service after every 5,000 km.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Enforce Shift Handover validation: a driver cannot close a shift unless the end location is recorded as a designated hub. Store trip logs and incident photos in Cloud Storage linked to each shift record. Implement a basic vehicle reservation system so fleet managers can pre-assign vehicles to drivers for upcoming shifts.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.vpcz2s8ameul">
      <t>18. Automotive Post-Purchase 'Voice of Customer' (VoC)</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A scheduled survey system for automobile dealerships that collects CSAT ratings at key milestones and awards loyalty points to respondents.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Surveys are automatically triggered (via email or SMS) at defined milestones: 2 days after vehicle delivery and 3 months after the first service. Implement a 5-star rating plus open-comment form. Flag any response with a rating of 2 stars or below and create a follow-up task for the service manager. Award loyalty points to customers who submit a completed survey.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Apply Survey Fatigue prevention: a customer must not receive more than one survey per 60 days. Provide basic reporting: average CSAT score per dealership and per service advisor. Prevent a customer from submitting the same survey trigger event more than once.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.eygax9n9zd2n">
      <t>19. Gated Community Utility &amp; Maintenance Billing</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A subscription billing system for residential societies with tiered water charges, automated late fees, and pro-rated billing for mid-month move-ins.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Generate monthly maintenance bills per apartment. Apply tiered water charges: a flat rate for the first 5 KL and a higher rate for consumption beyond that. Apply a flat late fee of ₹100 per week if payment is not recorded by the 5th of the month. Implement pro-rated billing when a new tenant moves in mid-month.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Support a Bulk Payment option where a resident pays 12 months in advance at a 5% discount. Track payment status and outstanding balances per apartment with a clear dues report. Store digital NOCs and lease agreements per apartment in Cloud Storage with a full audit trail.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.2mebxuw7e440">
      <t>20. Hospital 'Diet-Kitchen' Automation &amp; Patient Nutrition</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A hospital meal ordering system with patient diet restrictions, dietitian approval gating, and automatic cancellation on patient discharge.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Patient profiles record dietary restrictions (Low-Sodium, Diabetic, Liquid-Only) and allergens. Patients or their families order from a curated menu; the order is held for dietitian approval before being sent to the kitchen. Hard-block any menu item containing a flagged allergen from appearing in a patient's ordering menu. Support a scheduled meal system for standard ward patients.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>When a patient is marked as discharged, automatically cancel all their pending scheduled meals. Log all meals delivered per patient for a basic nutritional audit report stored in Cloud Storage. Notify the ward nurse if a scheduled meal has not been marked as delivered within 30 minutes of the scheduled delivery time.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.r2fjisyqejpp">
      <t>21. Fintech 'Circuit-Breaker' &amp; Multi-channel Alerting</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A multi-channel notification service (Email and SMS) with priority queues, user preferences, rate limiting, and digest batching.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Support two delivery channels: Email and SMS. Implement priority queues: Critical alerts are sent immediately while Informational alerts are batched and delivered once daily. Allow users to configure notification preferences at the category level (e.g., disable marketing emails). Implement per-user rate limiting to prevent notification spam.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>When more than 10 alerts of the same category are triggered for a user within one hour, batch them into a single digest notification. Track delivery status (Sent, Delivered, Failed) and implement one automatic retry for failed SMS deliveries. Automatically append required regulatory disclaimers to all financial alert notifications.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.tg1oir1ua0gv">
      <t>22. Real Estate 'Title-Deed' Verification &amp; Lien Registry</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A property document management platform with hierarchical access control, expiry alerts, and a basic digital signing workflow.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Documents are organized by property project. Implement hierarchical access: the Lead Bank sees all documents for a project, while individual homebuyers see only their own unit's documents. Send email notifications 90 days before a document (e.g., Building Permit, Fire NOC) expires. Store all documents in Cloud Storage with full version history.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Implement Lien Release: when a bank marks a loan as repaid, the associated title deed status updates to Released. Support a basic multi-party signing workflow where multiple parties upload signed PDF confirmations before a document is marked fully executed. Prevent duplicate property registration by checking unique survey numbers against the existing database.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <hr />
    <h3 headingId="h.us35p96lycw3">
      <t>23. Industrial B2B 'Scrap &amp; Recyclables' Auction House</t>
    </h3>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Elevator Pitch:</b>
      </t>
      <t> A forward auction platform for manufacturing plants to sell industrial scrap to manually verified buyers with auto-increment bidding and post-auction settlement.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Requirements:</b>
      </t>
      <t> Sellers list scrap lots with photos, estimated quantity, and material type. Registered and admin-approved buyers can place bids during an open auction window. Implement auto-increment bidding with a configurable minimum bid increment. After the auction closes, generate a settlement invoice with a built-in 10% weight variance tolerance applied to the final quantity.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Allow buyers to retract a bid only if they are not the current highest bidder; log all retraction attempts. Implement a basic dispute flag that a buyer can raise if received scrap quality does not match the listing. Store lot photos and weigh-bridge certificates in Cloud Storage linked to each auction lot.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
  </body>
  <header id="kix.drllf0pqobki">
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Boot41 Project Ideas</b>
      </t>
    </p>
  </header>
  <footer id="kix.kr9payhoz9l7">
    <p>
      <t>(c) 2026 Think41 Technologies Pvt. Ltd</t>
    </p>
  </footer>
</tab>
