<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tab id="t.vsi2vron9rou" title="Cover Letter" index="1">
  <body>
    <sectionbreak sectionType="CONTINUOUS" contentDirection="LEFT_TO_RIGHT" columnSeparatorStyle="NONE" />
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Sincerely,</t>
    </p>
    <p>
      <t>
        <b>Ramesh Sippy</b>
      </t>
    </p>
    <p>
      <t>ramesh.sippy@extrasuite.io | +1 (415) 555-0192</t>
    </p>
    <p>
      <t>January 15, 2026</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Hiring Manager</t>
    </p>
    <p>
      <t>ExtraSuite Platform Team</t>
    </p>
    <p>
      <t>Think41, Bangalore, India</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <h2 headingId="h.n1ylcbgunxzu">
      <t>Re: Principal Engineer, Developer Platform</t>
    </h2>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Dear Hiring Manager,</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>I am writing to express my strong interest in the Principal Engineer role on the ExtraSuite Platform Team. Having spent the last three years as Lead Engineer building the very foundation of this product — from the reconciler and serde pipeline to the service account identity model and mock API — I believe I am uniquely positioned to take ExtraSuite to its next stage of scale and reliability.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>When I joined Think41 in March 2023, ExtraSuite was a prototype with a fragile legacy diff engine that broke on tables, multi-tab documents, and nested bullets. I led the ground-up redesign of the reconciliation pipeline: a right-to-left structural diffing algorithm that converts XML document trees into minimal, correct Google Docs batchUpdate requests. Today, the reconciler handles every structural edge case — inner-slot inserts, section breaks, deferred header/footer IDs, multi-tab reindexing — and passes 372 automated tests, all verified against a pure-function mock that I built and validated against the live Google Docs API across 61 scenarios.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Beyond correctness, I care deeply about developer experience. The pull/diff/push workflow I designed lets an AI agent edit a Google Doc by modifying a handful of readable XML files — no API tokens, no JSON request crafting, no index arithmetic. The agent just edits text, and ExtraSuite handles the rest. This abstraction is what makes ExtraSuite genuinely useful to LLM agents rather than theoretically usable by them.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Prior to ExtraSuite, I spent nearly four years at Google as a core contributor to the Docs API — I helped design the batchUpdate request schema and the UTF-16 index model that ExtraSuite is built on top of. I have seen the API from both sides: as the engineer who built it, and as the engineer building tools that depend on it. That dual perspective has been invaluable in designing a reconciler that works correctly at the edges where the API behaves unexpectedly.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>I am excited about the roadmap ahead: expanding ExtraSuite to Forms and Calendar, deeper LLM integration, and the enterprise trust and audit features that will make ExtraSuite the default choice for AI-assisted document workflows. I would welcome the chance to discuss how I can contribute at the Principal level.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
    <p>
      <t>Thank you for your time and consideration.</t>
    </p>
    <p />
  </body>
</tab>
